Welcome to our training on the Brand Analytics top search terms report.
Brands enrolled in Amazon Brand Registry enjoy access to a suite of additional
selling benefits, including the Brand Analytics tool in Seller Central.
In this video, we'll review the features and functionality of one of the reports
you'll find in Brand Analytics top search terms.
This report provides brands with a broad view of customer search activity.
Instead of focusing on their brand, the report lists keywords that customers
have used to find and purchase products across the Amazon store.
This information can help brands suggest updates to the keywords associated
with their product detail pages.
Or they can use it to identify purchasing trends and advertising opportunities.
You can access the top search terms report and others in the Brand Analytics tool
if you're a seller internal to a brand enrolled in Brand Registry.
Simply select Brands in the main menu in Seller Central, then click Brand Analytics
or click All Brand Benefits, then locate the Brand Analytics card.
For more information about access to Brand Analytics and other Brand Registry tools,
see our modules in Seller University about requesting or managing access to
brand selling benefits.
After accessing the Brand Analytics tool, you can select top search terms
from the list of reports at the top of the screen.
The report lists keywords in order of search frequency.
You'll see the keyword customers used most at the top,
with all other keywords in descending order below.
In the row for each keyword, you'll see the three brands and categories
customers clicked most after searching with it.
Then you'll see the three products that customers clicked most after
searching with the keyword.
For each top-clicked product, you'll see an ASIN and title as well as a click
and conversion share percentage.
Click Share is the number of times customers clicked the product on search
results pages after using a keyword divided by the number of times
customers clicked any product.
For example, 10 customers searched the Amazon store using the term Backpack,
then clicked one product each.
If five of those customers clicked the same backpack,
its click share would be 50%.
Conversion share is the number of times customers purchased the product
after using a keyword divided by the number of times customers purchased
any product.
For example, 20 customers searched the Amazon store using the term
Mug and purchased one product each.
If 15 of those customers purchased the same mug,
its conversion share would be 75%.
When you first access the top search terms report,
it'll be defaulted to show you the search terms that Amazon customers
used the previous week.
You can use the drop down menu and date field to select a different time
period.
Keep in mind that data is generally available in brand analytics within
72 hours.
After selecting a time period, click the Apply button to refresh the report.
You can use filters to narrow the report to one or more top-clicked products
or to narrow it to a specific top-clicked brand or category or a single
keyword.
Click Show Filters and enter up to 100 ASINs in the first search bar
separated by either a space or comma.
Or use the other search bars to enter a brand name or keyword.
To filter by category, select it from the drop-down menu.
When you're ready to apply a filter, click the refine Results button
to refresh the report.
If you'd like to add or remove columns on the top search terms report,
click Customize Columns on the right-hand side.
Then check or uncheck boxes in the pop-up.
Click the Save button to return to the updated report.
To download a copy of the report, click the Generate Download button.
Then in the pop-up, select either Simple View to download the report you see on
screen or select Comprehensive View to download the report with all relevant
columns.
Click the Generate Download button to start your download, which you can
monitor by accessing the Download Manager.
Finally, if you want more information about how a specific metric is calculated,
click Metrics Glossary to see a set of comprehensive definitions.
On the Metrics Glossary page, you can expand each section to see additional
details.
We encourage brands to use all the features and functionality of the top
search terms report to gain insights into their performance in the Amazon
store.
Use it to suggest updates to the keywords associated with your product
detail pages.
Note trends in customer purchasing or develop advertising strategies that can
help drive traffic to your brand and products.
This concludes our overview of the top search terms report.
If you'd like step-by-step instructions for other brand analytics reports,
please see our series of modules in Seller University.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.